<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Seasonal Weather (Continued)</name>
  <packageId>Mlie.SeasonalWeather</packageId>
  <author>AaronCRobinson</author>
  <url>https://github.com/emipa606/SeasonalWeather</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.0</li>
    <li>1.1</li>
    <li>1.2</li>
    <li>1.3</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>[img]https://i.imgur.com/buuPQel.png[/img]
	  
Updated for Hardcore SK by Vile Heathen	  
Update of AaronCRobinsons mod
https://github.com/AaronCRobinson/SeasonalWeather

[img]https://i.imgur.com/pufA0kM.png[/img]

[table]
    [tr]
        [td][url=https://invite.gg/Mlie][img]https://i.imgur.com/zdzzBrc.png[/img][/url][/td]
        [td][url=https://github.com/emipa606/SeasonalWeather][img]https://i.imgur.com/kTkpTOE.png[/img][/url][/td]
    [/tr]
[/table]
	
[img]https://i.imgur.com/Z4GOv8H.png[/img]


SeasonalWeather
Extends weather to change based on season. Please comment and let me know any feedback about seasonal settings or potential related features.

Features
Each season has different weather commonalities for each weather type
All biomes have weather adapted a bit to fit each season. More to come.
Most biomes are less clear now and I think Jungles in particular will go more in this direction.
New weather types are added: Dust, Dry Duststorm, Foggy Snow, Cloudy, and Windy
New weather disasters are added: Wildfire, and Earthquake
Disasters can be disabled/enabled in mod settings
Growth rates are increased for plants by 20% during rainfall
Weather Drone has been added (maybe needs a better name). Weather can affect mood in rare cases (like a psychic drone).
Added Double Rainbow. Rarely after a weather event which contained rain, a double rainbow appears and improves moods.
Wildfires
Intvention will shorten the length of this event
Min length if fire is surpressed is about half a day
Min length without intervention is 5 days
Max length a quadrum
Translations
English
Turkish (by Slevilex)
Acknowledgements
HammerheadCow/IgnisGlacies for Windy, Cloudy, and FogSnow weather.

Special thanks to Pardeike's amazing non-destructive patching library, Harmony.

[img]https://i.imgur.com/PwoNOj4.png[/img]
[list]
[*] See if the the error persists if you just have this mod and its requirements active.
[*] If not, try adding your other mods until it happens again.
[*] Post your error-log using [url=https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=818773962]HugsLib[/url] and command Ctrl+F12
[*] For best support, please use the Discord-channel for error-reporting.
[*] Do not report errors by making a discussion-thread, I get no notification of that.
[*] If you have the solution for a problem, please post it to the GitHub repository.
[/list]
</description>
</ModMetaData>
