<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>

<ModMetaData>
	<name>Wood You Please</name>
	<author>VileHeathen</author>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.2</li>
		<li>1.3</li>
	</supportedVersions>
	<packageId>ViTech.HCSKWood</packageId>
	<modDependencies>
		<li>
		  <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
		  <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
		  <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
		  <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
		</li>	
	</modDependencies>
	<loadBefore>
	</loadBefore>
	<loadAfter>
	</loadAfter>
	<incompatibleWith>
	</incompatibleWith>
  <description>
Update 1.2 - 1/20/2020 - Added acacia wood.  
Update 1.1: No major changes, but the new mod Biomes: From The Ground Up, is meant to pair well with this mod.	  
	  
HEY! You want some planks? Planks come from trees. There's lots of different kinds of trees. Planks can be made into all sorts of cool things. Can you? Didn't think so. This is hardcore SK. It's hardcore, like the heartwood of a tree. Show these trees the respect they deserve. Now stop complaining and drink your maple syrup.
	    
I've started a blog and patreon for my mods! Check it out, and support me if you wish - I'm also taking commissions! 
http://patreon.com/vileheathen
		
Version A0.1  
This is super flipping early alpha. It's a huge overhaul of logs and planks, so I'm not entirely sure how it will affect all other parts of the game or other mods yet. If anything seems weird, recipes broken, etc, please let me know on the HSK Discord.

What does this mod change?
Logs and planks are unique to their tree species and have color and specs rebalanced for realism and a more distinctive gameplay based on biome. 
I highly recommend using this with the my new Hardcore Renovations mod which fully takes advantage of these new wood types in floors and walls.

Basic info:  

Felled trees now produce larger, but fewer logs (with Bamboo as the exception. It's not a tree anyway.), and can't be used as fuel except in advanced furnaces (TBD). A new woodsplitting spot (much like the butcher spot) allows colonists to split the logs into firewood which can be used for crafting redimentary things like arrows, clapboard floors and walls, as fuel, or can be further split into kindling for fueling torches, etc.

I. Wood is now divided into three categories (in order of the janka scale of hardness):

Softwoods:
	  Cecropia
	  Pine
	  Willow
	  Redwood
	  Cypress
	  Poplar
Hardwoods:
	  Maple
	  Teak
	  Birch
	  Oak
	  Bamboo
Ultra-hard:
	  Drago
	  Mangrove

Softer woods tend to offer less HP, but are often easier to work with and the trees are easier to cut. Technically, some of the softwoods are actually hardwoods, but I'm basing this off their actual hardness, not official designations.
Harder woods also produce more firewood since they can be chopped into smaller pieces.  
	  
II. Tree generation has changed.
	  1. Growing time and harvest amount has been adjusted for realism and balance. 
	  2. Most trees are now more likely to grow in groves. This means if you want to harvest a particular type of wood, you can target specific parts of the map to do so. Use the magnifying glass feature on the minimap or the Object Seeker to help find the groves.	  

III. New Woodsplitting Spot is an ingredientless building for splitting logs into firewood and kindling early game. Obviously slower than the workbench.

IV. Anywhere there was a vanilla wood log, there is now "firewood". Anywhere there was vanilla wood planks, there is now plywood. Plywood can be made out of scraps of logs or planks, much how patch leather is made. 
	  
Feedback is appreciated. Thanks!

Update Sept 26, 2021 - Lowered splitting spot workspeed, but also lowered recipe work. Also, you can now build the woodcutting table out of planks if you wish, for increased workspeed.	  

</description> 
</ModMetaData>